A Guide to the Woodbine Cemetery Records, ca. 1830-2006 (bulk 1940-2000): SC 0236
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 2: Administrative Files, ca. 1830-2002
  - Bound Book of Minutes, 1980–1989 (Box 66, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Business Records, 1898–2006
  This series contains material relating to the business side of Woodbine Cemetery from the years 1898-2006. The materials within this series relate to the cemetery's interactions with their customers and patrons. As such, it includes lists of lot owners, deeds, and contact information for customers. Among these materials are documents relating to disputes, and questions arising about specific plots or persons in the cemetery. Also included are newsletters, fund letters, mailing lists, and correspondence generating through interactions with the Harrisonburg community at large.
  - Memos Correspondence and Reports, 1960–1980 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Inactive Lot Owner Accounts, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Inactive Lot Owner Accounts, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1981–1983 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Advertising, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Harrisonburg Businesses, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Bulk Business Mail, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising, 1982–1985 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Government Marchkers, 1982–1984 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Equipment Maintenance, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Fees, 1979, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Sale of 481 East Marchket Street, 1982–1985 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Customer Correspondence, 1984–1985 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - W-4s and Withholding Certificates, 1972–1991 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Special Projects, 1984, undated` (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Independent Contract Agreement, 1984–1985 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Lots for Sale by Owner, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1982–1984 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Dun and Bradstreet, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Rock Locations, undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Map Segments, undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Burial Permits and Lot Sales, 1992–2002 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Special Fund Campaign, 1993–1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992–1995 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1996–1997 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1998–1999 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2001–2002 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – A, 1941–1975 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Albert, 1940–1944 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Allen, 1943–1944 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Altaffer, 1943, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Amiss, 1943–1944 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners –Armentrout, 1943–1978 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Armstrong, 1938–1954 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Auginbaugh, 1942–1948 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – B, c. 1938-1976 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Bassford, 1943–1976 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Bazzle, 1946–1947 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Berry/Beery, 1941–1958 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Billhimer, 1942–1957 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Bishop, 1944–1947 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Blackburn, 1940–1958 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Blakemore, 1943–1958 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Boyd, 1941–1948 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Bowers, 1944–1949 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Bowman, 1943–1957 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners –Bradley, 1943–1964 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners –Braithwaite, 1942–1965 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Brown, 1943–1978 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – C, 1925–1977 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Carrier, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Coffman, 1943–1957 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Clark, 1943–1956 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Christie, 1944–1947 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Conrad, 1945–1955 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Curry, 1945–1951 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – D, 1943–1979 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Davis, 1943–1959 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Dean, 1943–1958 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Dechert, 1943–1959 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Dillard, 1943–1951 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Dovel, 1943–1958 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – E, 1942–1966 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – F, 1942–1949 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Fleming, 1942–1944 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – G, 1942–1975 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners - Gilmer/Gilmore, 1944–1979 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Guyer, 1943–1965 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – H, 1939–1978 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners - Heatwole, 1945–1957 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Harnsberger, 1943–1958 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Harrison, 1943–1957 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Hawse, 1943–1950 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Hughes, 1943–1949 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – I, 1942–1961 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – J, 1941–1979 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Jones, 1947–1949 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – K, 1941–1976 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Kavanaugh, 1942–1954 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Kennedy, 1957 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – King, 1949–1959 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – L, 1942–1978 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Landes, 1942–1958 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Lam/Lamb, 1941–1959 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Liggett, 1943–1953 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Loewenbach, 1943–1958 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Long, 1945–1959 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Lucas, 1942–1956 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – M, 1941–1979 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Mahone, 1943–1950 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Masters, 1949–1953 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Mauzy, 1943–1949 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Mc, 1943–1978 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Miller, 1943–1953 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Moreland, 1943–1950 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Myers, 1943–1960 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – N, 1942–1964 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Neff, 1943–1959 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Nicholas, 1942–1952 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – O, 1942–1953 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Ott, 1942–1959 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – P, 1942–1975 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners - Partlow, 1942–1946 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Paul, 1943–1961 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Price, 1941–1961 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Pulse, 1943–1964 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Q, undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – R, 1941–1976 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Reherd, 1941–1960 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Rhodes, 1942–1959 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Rippetoe, 1942–1960 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Rohr, 1942–1950 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Roller, 1946–1956 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Roudabush, 1942–1944 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – S1, 1935–1951 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – S2, 1951–1977 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Sheehan, 1943–1956 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Snyder, 1943–1959 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Stephenson, 1943–1954 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Sullivan, 1943–1960 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Switzer, 1942–1957 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – T, 1943–1976 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Taylor, 1940–1960 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Tutwiler, 1942–1944 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – U, 1943–1948 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – V, 1942–1973 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Vanpelt, 1943–1947 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – W1, 1920–1950 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – W2, 1948–1979 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – Webster, 1941–1964 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Woodbine Lot Owners – XYZ, 1942–1958 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Anderson - SE QR 620, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Coughlin, 1983–1990 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Custer – NH 866, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Derrow, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Deyerle, 1989–1990 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Fristoe – NH 669, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Gentry - WH 839, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Kenton Burkholder Agreement, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Lambert – 918, 1988–1991 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Long Charlena – 920, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Ludholtz File, 1974–1996 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - O'Sullivan, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - M.D. And Joe Ann Neff, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Plume, Rutherford, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Ritchie, Virgil, 1990–1993 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Shifflet – SH 581, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Sowers – SH 856, undated (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Spangler Letter - Lot 890, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Thorne – 910, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Trippeer – W1/6 870A, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Wagner, Irene – 888 (6), 1989 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Warrern – Lot 189, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Whitmore, Michael B - #682,, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Welsh, Charles and Jane, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Lots for Sale, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Burial Log, 1988–1992 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Family Plots – Charts, 1943–1991 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Forms for Mike Martin, 1948–2002 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence to Answer, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Disabilities Awareness, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Mailing List, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Lots Purchased by Cemetery, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Notices of Abandonment, 1942–1951 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Bids, 1920–1939 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Extra Help, 1949 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Lots for Sale by Lot Holders, 1943–1959 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Lots with unused space, 1944, 1944 (Box 48, Folder 37)
  - Annual Assessments, 1986–1987 (Box 48, Folder 38)
  - Lot Assessments, 1997–1999 (Box 48, Folder 39)
  - Annual Assessment, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 40)
  - Lot Assessment Letters, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - Special Fund Letters, Contributions and Thank Yous, 1997–2001 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Letters, October 1999-May 2000 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Deed Forms, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Fairview Cemetery Questionnaire, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - EMU Financial Assistance, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - VA Dept. of Agriculture Application, 1990–1991 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986–1989 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Mailing List, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Special Fund Mailing List, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Lot Owners and Buried Persons, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Deeds, A-J, 1981–2005 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Deeds, K-Z, 1981–2005 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Extra Deeds, 1941–1981 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Inactive Lots and Assessments Owed, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Cemetery Brochure Data, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Repossessed Lots Through 1980, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Active Owner Accounts, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Lots in Question, 1947–1984 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Alphabetical List of Lot Owners,, 1950-07-22T00:00:00.000 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter, 1985–1987 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Cemetery Wall, 1940–1986 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Hottinger Loan, 1972–1983 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Memos, Correspondence and Reports, 1944–1981 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Perpetual Care Certificates, 1916–1968 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Endowment Contributions, 1982–1984 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Changes to Deeds, 1951–1984 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Deeds, 1945–1958 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Deeds A-B, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Deeds C-D, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Deeds E-F, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Deeds G-H, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Deeds I-K, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Deeds L-M, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Deeds N-P, 1898–1980 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Deeds R-S, 1898–1980 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Deeds T-Z, 1898–1980 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Lots Inventory, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Woodbine Paid-Out Documents [PHOTOGRAPHS], 1957- ca. 1977 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Perpetual Care Deeds, 1944–1962 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Customer Cards, A-D, ca. 1940- ca. 1990 (Box 54)
  - Customer Cards, E-R, ca. 1940- ca.2000 (Box 55)
  - Customer Cards, S-Z and Repossessed Lots, ca. 1940-ca. 1990 (Box 56)
  - Customer Cards, Extras, undated (Box 57)
  - Perpetual Care Customer Cards, A-Steele, undated (Box 58)
  - Perpetual Care Customer Cards, Stephens-Z and Atty and Trust Officers, undated (Box 59)
  - Customer Balance Cards, ca. 1950 (Box 60)
  - Burial Permits, 1946–1992 (Box 61)
- Series 4: Mausoleum Records, 1924-2006 Bulk, 1989–2006
  This series contains the information related to the management and fundraising efforts of the Woodbine Community Mausoleum from its founding in 1989 until it was acquired by Woodbine Cemetery in 2006. This includes financial documents, board minutes, owner information, and all other material relating specifically to the Mausoleum.
  - Account Statements, 1997–2002 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Account Statements, Duplicates, 1997–2002 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Account Statements, 2003–2006 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Account Statements, 2003–2006 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Receipts and Accounts, 1999–2005 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Financial and Administrative Papers, 1994-December 1996 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Portfolio Recommendation, 1998-12-01T00:00:00.000 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Mutual Fund Review, 1998-12-01T00:00:00.000 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Voided Certificates, 1924–2004 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Donations, 1995–2004 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Mausoleum Letters, 1989–2002 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Merger Proposal Letter, 2000 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - VA Tax Info, 1990–1993 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Trustees Annual Meeting Minutes, 1989–2006 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Insurance Papers, 1992–2001 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Community Mausoleum, 1989–1990 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Ownership Certificates, 1970–2000 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Founding Documents and History, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Documents, 1989–2002 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Crypt Community Mausoleum Letters, 1924–1988 (Box 64, Folder 4)
- Series 5: Ephemera, 1985–2000
  This series is comprised of general records that were maintained by the cemetery for posterity, including photographs of the cemetery, sesquicentennial celebration information, and various publications and information related to cemeteries.
  - Miscellaneous Product Information, 1985–1989 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - American Cemetery Magazine, August 1999-December 1999 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - News Stories About Cemeteries, 1987–2000 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Magazine Articles, 1985–1988 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Woodbine Sesquicentennial, 2000 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Woodbine History through 1998, 1998 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Information from Other Cemeteries, 1992–1998 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Woodbine Photographs, undated (Box 65, Folder 8)
- Series 6: Maps, 1913–1966
  This series is composed of maps and charts of Woodbine Cemetery and the Mausoleum, which show how the cemetery expanded during the 20th century.
  - Plan of Woodbine Cemetary Maps, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mausaleum map, 1925, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Segmented Map, 1928 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Planting Map, 1931 (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Labeled and Segmented Map, 1:10 Scale, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Maps of Woodbine Cemetary from map made July 1913, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mounted Annotated Map, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annotated Maps, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Woodbine Cemetery Map Books, 1953 (Box OV 3)
  - Woodbine Cemetery Map Books, 1953 (Box OV 4)